# STEVEN M. ERICKSON

# DIGITAL EXPERIENCE MANAGER



## CONTACT

Plainville, MA

508-579-0764

stevenmerickson.com

steven@stevenmerickson.com

linkedin.com/in/steven-michael-erickson in

# **PROFILE**

Highly capable marketing professional with 12+ years experience with B2B companies and a proven track record of successful lead generation, campaign strategy, and utilizing KPIs to drive results, brand identity, and optimizing omnichannel communications. Seeking opportunity to continue achieving and surpassing marketing targets with customer centric strategies.

# **EXPERIENCE**

• Lenze Uxbridge, MA

March 2022 - Present

## Digital Experience Manager

- Understand customer needs, perform competitive analysis, user testing and develop insight to aid in the development of the digital customer experience strategy and inform design decisions.
- Visualize concepts to represent user journeys, personas, goals and information models.
- Collaborate with key stakeholders to create, implement and optimize an indirect channel e-commerce strategy and other digital sales strategies.
- Assisting with the organization's digital transformation efforts.
- July 2018 March 2022

#### **Marketing Programs Specialist**

Responsible for identifying, developing, and managing the integrated marketing programs for Lenze's network of distributors.

- Maintained and enhanced key tools for distribution network.
- Developed and executed digital marketing campaigns for lead generation and brand awareness
- Led team in Americas market to relaunch e-commerce store.

# 

Westboro, MA

April 2016 – June 2018

#### **Associate Brand Manager**

- Gathered industry data and trends to support strategic development of lead generation marketing campaigns
- Managed launches and longer-term maintenance of marketing campaigns in various channels
- Leveraged internal data, lead primary market research initiatives, and accessed secondary research



Waltham, MA

April 2014 - April 2016

#### **Regional Marketing Coordinator**

Provided education, co-marketing, and collateral support to 40+ sales representatives for their accounts.

April 2012 - April 2014

#### **Associate Marketing Coordinator**

Assisted Regional Marketing Coordinators in their marketing efforts.

# **SKILLS**

- Figma
- > HubSpot
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- "
  HTML/CSS/JavaScript

#### **Brand management**

Email marketing

Market research

Digital marketing

Communication

Collaboration

Marketing strategy

German



# **EDUCATION**

### April 2020 - July 2020

# Nanodegree, User Experience

**U** Udacity

Three month course covering research fundamentals, prototyping, and analyzing performance of designs.

#### April 2020

## **UX Design Theory**

û Udemy

Crash course teaching the difference between UI and UX, creating wireframes and building prototypes with InVision, and reporting user testing results.

#### 2011 - 2014

## Bachelor's Degree - Marketing

snhu Southern New Hampshire University

GPA: 3.89, Magna Cum Laude Honor society: Delta Mu Delta